How to use 3D and 3D design?
I want to talk about a few parts
The first two are about why to use 3D and 3D design
I think because many teachers and classmates in our group are also using it
Everyone may know this part better
Maybe the focus is still on 3 and 4
Some of the designs we have in talent training
And some of the small achievements we have taught
The whole display
So why do we need this 3D?
We all know that the whole traditional clothing
The production cycle is long, the cost is high, and the modification is constant
Design innovation has also encountered some bottlenecks
Especially now that there are so many houses and buildings
In addition, our entire industry
In fact, the small unit quick-release custom mode and pre-sale mode that are presented
In fact, it is also very common
I think everyone is very clear about this
Just turn it over
Therefore, in fact, the demand for clothing design talents
It is now very obvious
One is not only to have design creativity
It's not just traditional
This structural craftsmanship
It must be a designer technology
What about this technology?
In the current industry
After so many years of generation
I think a very obvious one is 3D
From the earliest time
Everyone doesn't know him very well
To slowly get to know
In recent years
In fact, it is already a must-have ability
So I think this one
Including the 3D clothing designers we have been talking about in the past two years
Digital designers and so on
Some new positions are launched
For the entire clothing industry
The demand for talent is a new drive
So for teaching
It also raises a very obvious demand
So in general
In addition to traditional
Maybe now a lot of traditional designers are also learning 3D
As the first step of the school
To train people
Such a college student
Including some graduate students
Before he enters society
We still hope he can master this skill
So in terms of job integration
In the training of complementary talents
May have to do more work
Then the entire virtual design
In fact, this is also before
Everyone may have seen
This is actually an experiment we did before
That is to say
After using 3D
An improvement in the overall design efficiency
An infinite expression of creativity
In addition, it has an environmental sustainability effect
So it can be in our entire design
Achieve a visualization
This is the most obvious
Is a simulation of the effect of a needle
Especially a simulation of fabric properties
But here we may also
I don't know about other of us
May be in our live broadcast
There are also some teachers and students
Is there a similar problem?
In fact, what we encounter in teaching
A more obvious problem is
Students may pay more attention to this
The effect of my design has been realized
The outer outline of this dress has been realized
But it's about the properties of the fabric
This one
In fact, there is no special attention
So I think this one
From our current teaching
It should be a relatively weak point
Then
This one
We from the modeling effect
Achieve this one
There is also one of our experience
That is to say
In fact, students
After he did this 3D modeling
He is actually
The structure and craftsmanship he learned
This one
In fact, on the contrary
Is promoted
Because he can feel it clearly
I may have been
When learning samples
I don't know
This sample
He drew it
Because it's usually
Learn the sample first
Hand drawing
Many schools
He doesn't know
What it looks like
Then he may have to
Make it out of a craftsmanship
but
Not necessarily
All of them
Do it
Especially like us
In the structure
Talk about some
He will be very abstract
But in this three-dimensional
In fact
When we are doing
He is actually very intuitive
Can see
It turned out to be like this
So in fact
For his other courses
It is a very big touch
So the fabric
In fact
With us
For example
Clothing material class
In fact, it can also interact
But
We also have this idea
Currently
This one
Is relatively weak
In addition
It is in the actual application
Mainly a design sharing
And a five-point connection of the department
Now in the e-commerce section
On the sale
In fact, there are also many applications
Including some of us
Shijian
Or some of the pre-sales we are doing now
All can be in
We use the three-dimensional
This one
To do
In addition to what we just talked about
This sample is
A link between the sample
And promotion
This is
We have a deeper understanding
Then the whole
On its application
It is
The development of new products
This one
In our daily teaching
There are also
Some of the designs of the series
Design of creative clothing
Including some clothing development
In addition
Fashion
Matching and layering
Like some virtual windows
Virtual store
Some of these designs
And some pre-sales on the sale
In addition
This one
In fact
Now
A lot of
This scene
We have all seen
Can be realized
Digital people
Plus digital clothing
Plus digital scenes
It's completely virtual
And we
Now
There are also some traditional clothes
In the market
This kind of reconstruction
Including 3D
This one
Clothing museum
And so on
Then
The whole
This software application
In fact
Everyone is familiar
Basically
There are six
We summed up
Six models
Human model
Insert the sample
Mix
Three virtual
Adjust the fabric
Processing details
Then
The point
We see
Our own school
Some designs
Because
We did it very early
Our school
First of all
We said
A professional development
When we started
Actually we
We have this sense
Still relatively sensitive
So we are in
In 2003
In fact,
It is a professional direction
Just confused
In fact, it is an independent recruitment
A professional
Clothing design and engineering
Called clothing cdcm
So we
Because of this profession
We are in 2004
Started recruiting
Is an independent recruitment
A professional class
And then
Because of this profession
A process of construction
We are with
Many of the domestic and foreign
This kind of
Digitalized companies
Will be connected
More
This one
Li Ke Ge Bo
Not good
We are close
It used to be PJM
Anyway, there are many
Similar companies
Digitalized companies
We will do a lot of communication
So overall
Our professional design
Is in
Design
Sample production
This
Production process management
And soft manufacturing
In this field
Will be introduced
This digitalization
Information
Related
These resources
And some
Technology
Let him
In the entire course
A system
Will be reflected
In addition
With these
Some cooperation
With digitalized companies
There are
Buying donations
Including some
Strategic cooperation
Made a more complete
Digitalized
Fashion design
Or production
Laboratory
Like CED
We also have
This soft manufacturing
A flow line
ERP
Including our
Three-dimensional virtual
So we are in this
Combined earlier
So in
16 years
Because
Our school
The whole
Is all
We put this
CED profession
Below
Set a digitalized
This clothing
Direction
Ah
So this
Profession
Is us
From the beginning
When we do
In fact
We are a
The core
Is the fashion design
Project
The foundation
Is traditional
Our courses
Basically
Still reserved
Then
We are
Included
Is
Part of the computer
Such courses
For example
Programming design
We digitalized
App
Long-term software
Basically
Will give students
To do
That is
Increase his
App application
One ability
And he
In our industry
One ability to solve problems
So in
The latest
This new
We are also
Combined
With the latest
One of the
This
His development
We opened
This clothing
App engineering application
Clothing data
Clothing digital supply chain management
And so on
These courses
Are closely related to the development of this industry
Such a kind of connection
Then
Our 3D virtual
This design
Includes
Talent training
It is also
A relatively early
Because we originally
In 2003
When
In 2004
Opened this major
So we
Contact with this company
In fact
We are in
In 2007
Contacted
This 3D
At that time
It should be the earliest
It should be that
This software
Then
The earliest
We didn't
We mainly use this software
To carry out some related research
For example
We did it early
In fact
This
Three virtual
To do
Related to the properties of the fabric
Some research
Mainly with
This researcher
Then
Around 2010
We may
With this
Slowly
Go
Contacted
Also included
Some subjects
Some elective classes
We will continue to open
Then
In 2016
We are with us
Some companies
Do a deep cooperation
Then
We also trained a lot of people
In fact
Many
Now also
May be in our company
There are also some
Students we trained before
Doing some
This
As an employee of the company
Then in 2018
We set up a
Multiplied
3D virtual clothing design course
Is a
I will talk about it later
Then this year
We are
With our company
Cooperation
Opened this
Semi-professional and semi-classical
A statement
So overall
We said
We are from the education design
We are multi-layered
Divided
A teaching design
Multi-layered
That is
We did one
We ourselves think
Still a relatively
Is a three-dimensional
Such a course system
Is from our teaching plan
Professional class
In fact, it is relatively
Is in the theoretical section
Based on the basic function of this teaching
Then
We are equipped in the concentration time section
There will be a course design
This course design
In fact, it is a case-by-case realization
Then this course design
When we opened in recent years
Is with us
A theoretical class in front of us
A theoretical class
Is another course
Called brand clothing
This product project
Is a collaboration
That is, pre-release and post-release
We can just put it together
Then we will take a look later
A student's work
In fact, it may also be reflected
Then the third piece
Is that we are actually
A creative expansion outside the class
Then we opened the face
Is a related professional student
We opened a innovative experimental project
In addition, we also opened a door
Called innovative practical class
Such a
Some of this
All
It is equivalent to a second class
Such an event
Then this year
We are
Opened this micro-profession and micro-classes
In fact, it is to respond to our school
An overall
Currently we are called micro-professionals
Then it is mainly extended to the industry
Then this micro-profession and micro-classes
In fact, it mainly reflects the needs of enterprises
Or the needs of the industry
To be able to respond to this school
On the needs of talent
Then we are in
Students
Very
More
Small
It is not a burden for students
Probably in 12 to 18 such grades
Let him
For this
In this professional field
Or in this skill module field
Can quickly
Combine the needs of this enterprise
Or the needs of the industry
To achieve a skill improvement
Then this
We are equipped with this micro-professional certificate
And some of the enterprises
Is a certification
To prove that he has done this micro-professional study
Some certificates
In addition
We also actively recommend this student
Go to the industry to do this internship
Then mainly
It is also to promote students to be able to
Do a better job
Then from this division
Because through the previous one
We talked about this
More comprehensive
Such a teaching design
We are
We hope that students can be at different levels
Can get something
So the first one
Is our basic
Basis layer
In fact, basically
In our professional class
This piece is realized
Is to let students master this basic
A modeling function
Can master basic tools
Then be able to understand
The transition between the two and the three
Mixing
Including some paper adjustments
And some fabric texture
Add color settings, etc.
Some of these basic skills
Then all of this basic course
We are all in that
The course recording on the learning channel
This is actually what we recorded
Some of the videos
That is, in each piece
According to this version
We will insert a lot
It's all about our own classes
This teaching group
Some of the classes we recorded
Then the students can be in class
He can also go
Very convenient to do learning
So you see us
Although we have listed so many classes
In fact, we have very few classes
Like our professional class
In fact, there are two classes
There are 32 classes
Then the concentration time is one week
In theory, one week
We are counting 30 classes
Expand the course
In fact, there are less than 20 classes
So in fact
In such a limited number of students
We want to let him
Can better master this
Our whole
This virtual design skill
Can create something
So we use it a lot
In this recording course
Because this is recorded very carefully
So the students basically
According to us
Recording this course
If you do
No need to guide
It can basically be realized
But we have also encountered some problems in the past two years
Including
Just the same
We are with our company
There is also a lot of communication
Will find
May be
In our course
More
It is inclined to
His sample
From two-dimensional to three-dimensional
A realization
Then the students
I am also interested in this
Because he
He is more intuitive
See
My two-dimensional
It turned into three-dimensional clothing
It looks like this
But he may have overlooked
A lot of details inside
This piece may emphasize
It will be less
This is one
In addition
It is also limited to
Is the equipment of the school
One of the effects
We are in this whole
A post-production
This effect
It will be less
Even
That is to say
We sometimes put this
The particle monitor is very small
Maybe our computer
Just a little bit
Can't move
So
In the whole
This is perfect
It is our
This is more
The effect of this
Is more
Weak
This is also
We have encountered
A relatively obvious problem
Then
The second
Is the advanced layer
The advanced
We may go more
Let the students emphasize
This
For example
Different fabrics
It is in this
The texture of the clothing
And it reflects
A physical attribute
Includes
Some of us
Like this
Sound
Clothes
Some of its sound
Distance
And some
This kind of
Up and down
Such
This is also
Some of our students
Some of his
Some of the
High quality
And also
The overall accuracy of the board shape
To improve the fabric
One of the general accuracy
From the perspective of the high street
We are hoping
This student
Can be
This is learned
This basic knowledge
Can be applied to him
To his
Some graduation design
The creation of works
Through some
Interaction
To modify the sample
Refresh the creative
At the same time
Through
The fabric
More adjustments
To achieve
Some natural
Folding
Etc.
for students in design class to realize their graduation designs.
We also encourage students to show and plan
some of the works of virtual fashion show.
Of course, this is what I just mentioned.
Because of the limitations of our equipment,
it is not particularly effective.
So this is also one of our key points.
Then in the application of the entire teaching,
we also hope to be able to apply it to various sections.
For example, some of the tools on the market.
We hope that it is in the teaching of brand fashion design and planning
to have a timeline.
Then in the teaching of our fashion room,
we will combine one of them with the one of the digital museum.
Another one is that we have done a
Ming Dynasty palace official virtual sewing experiment project.
This is a first-class city in Shanghai.
Then it will also be included in the teaching of the fashion room.
Then,
with the combination of fashion engineering and engineering,
we made one here.
This is not what we did ourselves.
This is what we edited.
It is a company that makes people's masks.
It is a screenshot of a website.
In fact, it is traditionally made of real people's masks.
Because in recent years,
there have been more changes in the application of digital people's masks.
So they also make digital people's masks.
They may pick people from all over the world.
Then,
according to the fashion style of different countries,
there are some needs to make digital people's masks.
So this is what we do with the human body measurement and clothing style in the public school.
This piece of content is to do some combination.
Turned over.
Then we have completed some cases in the whole teaching.
Just to share with you,
it's mainly students.
Then in the training plan of the students,
this intensive part is what I said just now,
this one-week class.
Then this one-week course,
we are with us,
just like I said,
the brand clothing design and planning course to link.
This link is because in my class,
there are very few classes.
But we also hope that it can be completed,
from planning to this effect picture,
to a complete process of realization.
So we will use it.
It's our previous course.
Let's see if I can click it.
This course,
it completes some planning cases.
Then in this planning case,
we will let it,
put it in this planning,
plan to do this effect picture,
to be realized in 3D.
So it's the one in front of it,
it's all they do.
This one,
ah,
some atmosphere board,
color board,
ah,
and so on.
Ah,
ah,
put some design ideas,
fabric choices,
ah,
are all reflected in this.
Ah,
then,
this is one of his first meetings.
Ah,
we are engineering students.
maybe just the first meeting of this piece of,
ah,
this painting of this piece,
it's not a little bit of a failure.
Ah,
ah,
then this is,
they,
ah,
find the relevant,
this costume,
ah,
this is a food.
Ah,
we also let him,
in fact,
is to do two homework in this course.
Ah,
it's a week,
we are in a week of this course.
He is one,
that is,
he is the first meeting of this work,
to be realized in this 3D.
Then,
at the same time,
we let him go to find a,
ah,
related theme,
or no matter,
different themes can also be,
is another one of the style of,
this clothing of food,
ah,
let him put this food photo of this clothes,
to be able to use this 3D to realize,
and then to compare,
ah,
the effect of this realization.
And this is,
ah,
we,
this classmate,
ah,
this is,
we are one person to complete a part,
not a group to complete,
ah,
are all personally completed.
So this is,
ah,
this,
this classmate,
he completed his own hand-made,
this 3D,
ah,
this is him,
that is,
this set of clothes is actually his early,
this existing product,
ah,
his one,
the effect of 3D realization.
Then,
after this effect is done,
he will,
in the end,
give him a show,
a show,
of,
because it is also relatively simple.
That is,
what we just said,
must say,
we research the problem,
so he,
ah,
basically,
what do we find in the desktop,
I can not see.
Ah,
ah,
然后第二个呢就是
我们把这个还是这个时间的这个课程啊
就是我们这个一周的这个课程设计
我们就是在每一年上课的时候
它可能正好这个主题不一样
所以这次呢
这是去年我们上课的时候
就是正好我们学院里有一个旗袍大赛
然后我们就把这个课程呢
就跟我们这些旗袍比赛结合起来
就把我们旗袍比赛里面
他们选出来的一些优秀作品
用我们这个三维去做了实现
然后我们就把这个课程呢
这个是然后接下来呢
这个分享的这个呢
是我们把这个三维呢
跟这个设计专做的一个培养
做的一个结合
这个学生呢
他就是做这个课程呢
做了一个海拍旗袍创新的一个设计
然后从他到这个设计稿
然后用做了一个三维实现
然后最后的一个作品的一个实现
整体呢还是比较完整的
然后还有一个呢
是我们在本科毕业设计里面
也有一部分这个
用这个三维去做的一些作品
那么这个是我们去年的
这个学生做的
就是做了一个少数民族的服装数字展示
他做了一系列的产品
也把它做到
一个自己做了一个很简单的建筑
里面
因为毕业设计呢
其实他们时间也挺短的
在这个有限的时间里面
随时随身的命运
这个很难承担
另外呢
就是我们在课程里
刚才讲到我们有一个
礼服虚拟创新设计的
这样一个实践课
这个实践课呢
其实就是二十个学生
这个时间更短
我们就上个五周课
然后
而且这个专业
这个课程里面很多都是跨专业的学生
所以也是借助于我们前面的
这个录制的一些视频
另外我们也是其实对学生来说
还是催的比较紧的
我们就让他们在很多的这个时间去课下去学习
那么这个课我们的操作方式是什么呢
就是他学完这个基本功能以后呢
我们早一些
因为他很多是跨专业的
他可能不具备这个设计能力
所以我们会找一些现有的一些礼服
比如说这种其实就是网上的一些
包含一些这种秀场的
然后呢
让他把这个礼服的这个效果呢
用三维把它实现出来
然后自己去做一个对照
包含这个面料花纹
他们就可以自己去做设计
我们打分的时候呢
也会对照他的这个实现的程度
还有整体的一个完成
完成度和完成的效果
来做一个打分
另外呢
就说我们把这个3D呢
其实我们也在公校学研究里面
包含一些本科和研究生里面
作为一个辅助工具来使用
这个呢
其实是我们一个学生
他在做课题的时候
他做了一个呼吸
那么在这个呼吸里面呢
他就做了一个不同角度的这个压力
他的一个分析
那我们就做了一个呼吸的这个创新的
这个分割是他自己做的
然后呢
他把
他在三维里面做出来以后
在不同的这个肌肉部位去看他的一个压力
那可以在不同的角度下
就跟我们这个是真人的这个使用
和他的虚拟里面做了一个对应
来去看他的一个压力的分布情况
那么其他方面呢
其实我觉得这么多年下来
我们觉得整个这个3D
对于我们科研方面
其实也是有促进的
比如说我们有老师拿到了这个上海市艺术基金
包含教育部的人文社科基金
他全部都是围绕呢
就是这个3D在这个传统服装的还原和一些这种保护性传承方面做的一个研究
那上海市呢
去年有个AI项目
我们做这个AIGC的一个深层式的一个服装设计
也有一个项目
另外这些项目呢
在在这个开展的过程中呢
其实是反普的教学的
比如说明朝官服服务员研究
我们就做在毕业论文里面
还有些汉服的创新设计啊
就让学生来做一些毕业的设计
那教学方面呢
我们也有这个上海市一流课程啊
包含我们做的一些相关的课程建设项目
比较明显的呢
在学生就业上其实也是促进学生的一个就业领域和贴近行业需求的这方面的就业
那近几年其实我们在这块的就业也是比较多的啊
包含我们刚才讲的在我们科罗公司其实也有很多我们自己的学生
那么从应用趋势上来说呢
其实大家可能
现在
也体现体体验的比较明显啊
刚才正好余老师也讲到了就是这个IGC的包含人工智能跟3D的一些啊这个结合啊
那我们今年其实申请一个微专业呢
就是这个AIJC的数字虚拟时尚设计啊
另外一个就是我们也申请了一个叫虚拟服装的创新设计啊
就是在这个方向上去做的啊
还有就是跟一些虚拟现实技术之间的一些结合啊
然后呢
可能在整体展示上的这种
这种在线化呀
数字孪生啊
一些VR AR等等技术啊
还有我们整体的这个展示上其实还有很大的这个空间
对于后续呢
我们可能也会在这些方面的做更多的尝试啊
把它纳入到这个教学里面啊
另外在这个教学上的还有一个比较深的体会就是我们可能要更多的去跟行业去做一些融合和交流啊
因为呃之前呢
就是我们公司跟我们去做沟通啊
跟我们去做沟通啊
我们也一直觉得就小贾跟我们来做沟通 She always communicates with us
我们觉得我们最大的一个痛点就是说可能我们在教学生我们觉得我们最大的一个痛点就是说可能我们在教学生
但是呢
嗯
按照我们的这个想法可能教了很学生很多东西按照我们的这个想法可能教了学生很多东西
但是企业到底需要什么
其实我们不是特别是特别的了解这个细节
我们也知道我也知道
铁是需要啊
有这个岗位的需求
但是它具体在这岗位上它对这个学生的细节性的一些呃这个技能要求是什么
In fact, we are not very clear about it.
So maybe in this area,
we think that if we promote student employment,
including students to be able to solve more practical problems,
maybe we need to do more work
to integrate with the industry in the future.
Overall,
we think that after so many years,
through lectures, time operations,
including some cases,
we actually get the effect.
We think from the feedback of students,
our own teaching team
is still good.
Some student works
can also be done more completely,
especially in terms of their skills.
Many students have skills,
they are very confident,
they like it more.
So there is also promotion in terms of employment.
What is not enough?
I feel that it is more obvious,
maybe it is a limitation of our software and hardware,
which makes us actually have a lot of this kind of rendering,
or some details of the effect
are not really able to be reflected.
In addition, in the actual teaching time,
it may encounter this problem,
that is, the difference in student control is relatively large.
This is relatively obvious,
that is, in the same class,
you go to them in the same progress,
some students do very well very quickly,
some students can't do anything well.
So this is also a bit of a headache.
In the end, of course, the results are good or bad,
it can only be reflected in this.
But we still hope in the actual teaching,
all students can still have a good time.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much,
thank you very much,
thank you very much.
I also hope that in the future,
I will have a similar level of understanding,
so in this area,
I may be able to do some exploration in subsequent teaching.
Overall, I will talk about so much.
Thank you everyone.